You now have the repository open.
We're going to make a small change to this README
file and push it back up to the GitHub
repository, just to prove that the
vscode integration is working correctly.
I've clicked on the name of the file in
the left hand side, in the Explorer, and
we'll add a little bit of text into it.
"Lab files for  workshop."
This is the link to the Citadel Terraform workshop.
Make that change and save it. You've
got the round dot here to show there are
unsaved changes. CTRL+S saves.
At that point
the Git symbol on the left hand side
should now show there's one file
file which has got changes. That's
the pending change. If I click on that
you can see we've got "SOURCE CONTROL: GIT"
which means it's found the Git
executable in the operating system path.
That's really key for those of you
using Windows 10 with the Windows Subsystem
for Linux. Installing git into the
Windows Subsystem is a good thing to
do, but it's the git installed at the
operating system level which is required,
so it needs to be in Windows system
path.
If I hover over the file name we can be
selective as to which changes we stage.
The process is two step. Stage files, then commit
files, which puts them into the local
repository. We can then push the commit up
to the main repository over in GitHub.
I'm just going to click on the `+` to
stage the change. It moves from
"Changes" through into "Staged Changes".
When we commit we
always have to have a message. I'm
just going to enter "Updated readme file".
Click on the tick to commit.
That has placed it locally into the
repository. You can see down in the status
bar that it's now showing there's one
commit which needs to be pushed up to the
GitHub repo. I can click on the sync icon in the
status bar or on the ellipsis (...)
and then do the "push".
The sync symbol will rotate round and
it'll take a couple of seconds to
replicate and now you're commit has been
pushed up. So now if you were to go back
into your GitHub repository, so go back
to your browser and go into the repo.
Refresh the README page and
you should see the change.