OK, so our template works but it's very
hard coded as it stands. We're going
to open up a couple of the properties to
the users as parameters. In the
parameter section you define, essentially
declare, which parameters are expected or
required from the user. I've put the
cursor between the two curly braces, hit
enter to go down and indent as before and if
I then type 'armp' then that will
filter down the snippets list and the
second one down is arm-parameter.
That's what we need within this section.
It's automatically highlighted 'parameterName'.
I'm going to put in ''storageAccount
using camelcase, so lowercase
the beginning and new words begin with
a capital (letter).  It's got a yellow
underline because we're not using it yet
anywhere within the template. When you
hover over any warnings or errors within
your template it will show some tooltip
about that.  There's a number of
different types that we can have for our
parameters, There could be strings or
integers or booleans or arrays or
objects or securestrings or secureobjects,
so a number of different things that
we can have within this.  We're going
to keep it simple as this is just a string.
I'm going to be structured
about this and put it in a metadata
description as well to describe the
parameter we've just created.  So "Name for
the storage account", and that's our
first variable. Now we're not actually
using that anyway yet, because we still
have our hard-coded values so that's the
bit that we want to replace so where I have
'richeneystgacct'.  Now you
notice that when I double clicked on that,
it says 15 selected characters down
there in the status bar.
It's because the first one is selected,
but it's also highlighted one which
matches it. This is one of the great
refactoring aspects of using vscode. If
you type CTRL+F2 at this point then
that will select all matching strings
for that, so you can see now in the status
bar it shows two selections and all 30
characters are selected. I can then hit
delete and I'll get rid of those. OK,
the other thing you want to be very
structured about is how you add in
functions.  This is going to be our first
function. Within our empty double
speech marks I'm going to do square brackets,
open square brackets, and you can see
what I do that it automatically creates
a new bit of intellisense for the
different functions.
If I type in "par" I should see
parameters comes in at that point. If I
tab over then it automatically puts in
the round braces. Add in a single quote
and then it will give you an Intellisense
based on the parameters which you have
defined up top. So because we've only
got storageAccount that's showing up. If
I tab that over that populates that and
then to finish off that function we then
have square brackets. All functions
have got speech marks and square
brackets surrounding them, that's the
format of these and then we have
"[ parameters('storageAccount') ]"
as a string. That's then referencing
whatever the user puts in at the top.
And you can see that it's done that for both the
name and also for our tags.displayname
as well. OK, just going to save that as
it stands. Right, we're going to add in a
second parameter and this one's going to have
a couple of additional properties.
One thing which is very handy is if you
hover over near the row numbers then you
can see these plus and minus symbols
come in, so you can click on them to then
shrink that up. You can see that is
basically the end brace for that parameter value.
The other thing which it does within vscode is
that if you are next to a brace - if you're
moving around - then it will show you
which matching brace there is. So you can
see that's the one I expect to see for
the value of storage accounts, the
storageAccounts name:value is
this object. If I do a comma there and
then go down with enter, then it enables
me to put in the second parameter. This
one we're going to call 'accountType'.
Again it's going to be a
string and it's going to be essentially
the SKU for the storage account.  Now
we're going to add in a couple of
additional parameters into this.  A default value
which is going to be standardLRS,
and also a list of permitted values,
allowed values, so if I'm there and I hit
enter and then put in speech mark again
the Intellisense kicks in it and it shows
defaultValue so I can tell you that tab
it over and then put in standard_LRS
And then if I do the same
for the allowed values that
automatically puts in an array for me
and then I could say okay so
"Standard_LRS" is one, and I'm going to
have "Premium_LRS"
and then finally
"Standard_RAGRS".
So then we've got that fully described.
Again we're not yet using it. We've got
the warning for that with accountTypes.
If you see a list of warnings or any
syntax errors, if you do CTRL+SHIFT+M and
then that'll bring up all the Problems
you have with them so it says here that
it's accountType is never used. Just
close it off again and we see that's
right because we've still got it hard-coded
within our resources section. If I get
rid of that I can then do the same as
before and use the Intellisense to
automatically enter in our accountType
within that and then save the file.