OK, let's add a storage account
resource into this empty template.
Move the cursor down inbetween the
square brackets which denotes the
resources array.  (You can obviously have
multiple resources within a template.)
Hit enter, it will drop down a line and
automatically indent neatly for us.
If you then type in "arm-stg" then that
will bring up the storage account
snippet. It automatically highlights
"storageAccount1" which is used both
for the name and for our displayName tag
which is a bit superfluous but we'll keep
it in there. I want you to replace this with
something which is unique for you.
I'm going to put in my alias and then
"stgacct" afterwards. This needs to be
globally unique as this forms part of the
FQDN, the fully qualified domain name,
which is used to access the various HTTPS
endpoints for blob, for file, for table,
for queue, and therefore it needs to be
globally unique. So enter in your
storage account name so it's unique.  Maybe add
a few numbers at the end to make
sure. The naming conventions for that can
be between 3 and 24 characters and
alphanumeric, all lowercase. Once you're
done, CTRL+S to save.