In this lab you have entered
parameters in a couple of different
ways.  You've been prompted for the values
interactively if it is a required
parameter and you haven't specified at
any point. That's at submission time
using the CLIs. The other place
is specifying the values inline.
PowerShell creates those additional
switches on the fly based on the name of
those parameters, which is why you can't
have parameters in your templates for
PowerShell which conflict with any
existing names such as "name".  For the
CLI you've got a couple of options there
either specifying JSON or you can
specify name=value pairs in
a space delimited list. What we're going
to do now is going to create a parameter
file and this is very useful
particularly if you have multiple
customers or partners and you want to
specify a different parameter file for
information specific to that particular
customer.
We're going to create a new file.
In our lab1 folder I'm going to create a
new file and that's going to be called
azuredeploy.parameters.json.  You can
call it anything you like but this is the
convention. As you can see that's
opened it at the top. Now you can use
CTGRL+ALT+LEFT and RIGHT to move
these around.
Or you can drag and drop and snap them now
using vscode. The files are now side by
side. I'm also going to do CTRL+B to
close down the sidebar and give ourselves a bit
of space.
I can see which parameters we have there.
Now I've got focus within the parameters.json
file and if I type "armp" then it
should automatically show the skeleton
for the parameters. Notice this has a
different schema compared to the main
azuredeploy.json. It's very limited in
what it can have. It just has a parameter
section as well as the schema and
content version. The parameter
section itself is also fairly limited as to
what it can have. I'm going to enter in
two parameters here. Again, type "armp",
but this time rather than choosing skeleton, or
arm-parameter, which is what we used in the
main azuredeploy.json when we're actually
declaring our parameters,
we're now going to specify a parameter
value. And that parameter value
is going to be storageAccountPrefix
and I'm going to specify a value which
is going to be "richeneysa", just to
show it's different to stg, which is
the default value on the left hand side.
If I move the cursor to there and
then if I put a comma, then enter, then we
should be able to put in another
parameter value.  Now we're going to
go for accountType and the value you're
going to have here is going to be
"Standard_LRS" which again is the
default, but we're going to make it
explicit within this.
Again there should be no problems
in that file. There, as you can see, we can
shrink up parameters and it closes
everything down. We can close down the
individual parameters within it and they
will be neatly aligned.  That is a good
parameter file. If we then open
up the area, go back into the lab 1 folder
so now we've got both the azuredeploy
and parameters file. If you want to
submit using these then you can do
"az group deployment create" and then
specify again the resource group
we're submitting into, which is lab1,
the template file, azuredeploy.json,
then the parameters,
rather than having name=value
as a list, we're going to use the @
operator to signify that it's a file.
Enter "@azuredeploy.parameters.json".
That is the full command for the submission.
Press enter then again it will
validate both of those files.
If everything is good then it will submit
those and we should get the resulting
storage account with richeneysa
as the prefix instead of our default.