OK, so we're going to create a resource
group on the command line and then
deploy our small template into that
resource group. Some of the commands can
get quite long so I'm going to use
CTRL+B to toggle the sidebar and then
you can see we're in the arm-workshop
directory. I'm going to move down into
the lab1 folder which is where the
azuredeploy.json file actually
sits. Just 'clear' that to tidy that up. I'm
now going to create the resource
group so 'az group create' then the name
of our resource group which will be
lab1 and then location-wise put that into West
Europe as we will do all the resources.
That'll take a second or two to go
through. If you find yourself
persistently deploying into the same
location and you want to shorten some of
the command line arguments you're using
personally (rather than something
scripted) then have a look at `'az configure'
because then you can set that as a
default within that. OK, so now we've got
our resource group I'm going to do an
'az group deployment create' and then I'm going
to give this a name of job one. This is the
name of the deployment job you'll see in
the resource group when we have a look
in the portal later on.  If you don't
specify a name for the job it will just
take it from the basename of the file that we're
using. So ours is called azuredeploy.json,
it'll be called azuredeploy,
deployed but we're going to specify our
jobname here. I'm going to select
the azuredeploy.json file that we have
in this folder. I'm just using the
autocomplete for that, and then the
resource group are going to submit into
which is lab1. I hit enter there then
it should take a look at that file,
validate it and then submit it through
the ARM layer and show that it's running
at this point. If we then give that
about 30 seconds then it will come up
with something that's completed.