Now we're nicely generating a
more unique storage account name using
our variable expression.
It would be useful to have that output
from the deployment so we know
which name has been created for our
storage account. You can do this
within the output section.
Move the cursor so it's between the
two curly braces and then hit enter.
It'll drop down and indent and then you
can give a name for your output.
I'm not going to be very inventive.
It's called storage account and
takes an object itself.  So if I
hit enter to drop down within that.
It has a couple of properties.
One is "type" and the other's "value".
If I tab over from "type" it allows
a number of different values, that is the
list of possible values.
I'll select "string" and
tab it over, then do comma to go down
to the next line.
The "value" is our last remaining property.
Add in the "[variables('storageAccount')]".
Single quote then storageAccount
is automatically populated for
us and then do square bracket to close
it off. That's another valid
template with no problems (using CTRL+SHIFT+M).
I can save it now. If you find
that for some reason your indentation has
gone a bit messy then one of the
nice things you can use is the JSON
Tools which has been provided as one of
the extensions. That was put in by
Eric Lynd and I've got that installed.
That enables you to do two things.
One, you can do ALT+M together to minify
everything, which can be very useful if
you are doing program code and you want
to shrink something down.
Or you can do CTRL+ALT+M and that'll prettify
it, expanding it out and based on your spaces
(setting) for your tabbing, it'll indent it
and then put all the nice little lines and
everything else so everything is where
it should be. That will only work if
your JSON is syntactically good, so
you'll need to fix any syntax errors
first before we can use those. It's a
great way of tidying up your templates
if you've managed to get yourself into a little bit
of an
indentation mess.