Before we can create a resource group
and submit the template into it, we need
to log in to Azure.  The good news is once
you've logged into Azure then you'll be
logged in for about a week.  If you do
CTRL+' or go through
View and then Integrated Terminal
then this will pop up. This is the Bash
version, you may want to set up the
PowerShell version. I'm going to type
in 'az login'.  I've already logged myself out
to go through this process again.  Now
this should automatically open up a
window with the code - it's a bit
slicker than it used to be - and then you go
through the credential process, which for
me is just clicking on that, and then
it will authenticate you using
multi-factor authentication if need be
and get you logged in.  Now if like me you
have multiple subscriptions then you can
do 'az account list'. I'm going to do that in
the table format rather than the coloured
JSON (jsonc) you see there. That'll
list out my multiple subscriptions. I'm
going to pick this one here, take that
code, and then if I do 'az account set
--subscription' and then paste in that
subscription GUID and that should show
the right one.  You can always show at any
point to which one you're in, your
context, if you do 'ad account show' and
that'll show you which subscription you're
in and also whether or not you're a person or if
you're a Managed Service Identity (MSI) or if you
are logging in using the Service Principal (SP)
but for most of you, you''ll be a user.