OK, so let's get in the habit of
actually saving our files and
in a strcutured way by committing them locally
to the repository and then pushing those
changes up into GitHub. You can see
now we've got the change that we've
saved, into the file over here on the
left hand side.  The source control symbol,
the Git symbol, is now showing that
there's one file which is changed. We
click on that and we can see it's listed.
If you hover over that you will be
able to click on the '+' which will
then stage that change locally ready to
be committed.  We can add a message in -
I'm just going to put in the 'Initial
commit' into the box there  - then if you
hit CTRL+ENTER at the same time
then that'll commit the change into your
local repository.  At this point in time
it's only local and there's nothing pushed
up into GitHub. You've got a couple of
ways to do this but the easiest way of
doing it is to hover over the sync symbol
here.  For you it should should show
there's nothing to come down and one
change to go up.   And then you can click
on the sync and it will whirl round and
then commit those changes up into the
GitHub repository under your ID.