OK, so if you've got everything set up
then this should be how your screen
currently looks. If you hover over the
ARM-WORKSHOP bar and click on the new
file icon - you can do CTRL+N as well if
you prefer - and then type in
"lab1/azuredeploy.json".  It will
create the file and the folder at the
same time and you can see it's focused
automatically on the pane on the right
hand side. If you type "arm!"
at that point then it will
select the skeleton template from the ARM
snippets. If you don't see the ARM
snippets then double check everything you've done
for the set up. You should have a
snippets file which you imported at some
point which you'll find down here within
Settings and User Snippets.  If it
does work then when you hit enter you should
see the default template come in. You'll
notice there's a round dot which
shows there's unsaved changes, up on the
tab.  If I do CTRL+S that will then save it,
now we have saved the changes.  Ready to go.