OK, so our template is now a bit more
functional and we can specify a couple of
parameters.  But it does rely on the user
specifying a storageAccount name which
turns out to be globally unique which is
probably a bit of a big ask. We're
going to change this a little bit from a
parameter to a variable, where we're
going to take a prefix which the user
can specify (but we'll have a default in
there) and then we're going to append
some characters to that to give it a
good chance of being unique. Now, if you
remember, the actual storage account
name needs to be between 3 and 24
characters, must be lowercase, and can
only include alphanumerics, so it's quite
specific as to what's allowed.
Let's start making some of these changes.
In the parameter section I'm going to
turn that from storageAccount to
storageAccountPrefix, and include that
there and in terms of description "Prefix
for the storage account name".
We're going to create storageAccount
as a variable and we could just
have that directly mapped onto
parameters and then storageAccountPrefix
(which is now popping up there) so that
would be a 1:1 for that.  But what we
want to do is concatenate
a uniqueString() on the back end of
this and then we want to make sure it
is in lowercase and finally we're
going to make sure it doesn't come in
too long. Let's have a quick look at
some of the functions you can use. If you go
into the address bar and https://aka.ms/armfunc
then that'll take you straight
through to the ARM functions area.
We'll be doing a couple of string functions.
There's number of different
function areas so you can do numerics,
there's information about the current
deployment or existing resources, some
comparison ones that we'll touch on
later in the labs around conditional
deployments, and also some more complex
functions for arrays and objects. Here
we're going to use a few which are quite
commonly used. And concat() is one of the
ones which is very commonly used so that
enables you to take multiple strings and
join them together.
We'll also be using toLower() which
lowercases, and finally we'll be using
uniqueString(). Now uniqueString is a
little bit badly named in that it
doesn't always create a unique string. It
will always create a hashed variable, as it
says deterministic, based on what you
seed it with.  So if you give it the same
seed it will give you the same hash
result each and every time which is
actually very useful to us.  Let's go
back and start putting some of these
things together so we can see how the
nesting looks. I'm going to get rid of
the argument I've got there.
The first one I'm
going to put together is to have the
toLower.  OK, so we're going to make sure
everything's lowered after it.  And I put
the square bracket after it just to
finish that off.  Now a little hint if you
want to keep having the Intellisense
come up, do a double space, and then move
the cursor back in between the two spaces
and then if you do something like concat()
then it'll come up.
(Or you can use CTRL+SPACE.)
Our first value is going to be our
parameter for storageAccountPrefix and
then we're going to put a suffix string
after that.  So let me just put 'suffix' in
as a string at the moment.
We can see that it's
going to be accepted as a function
expression. OK, so now we're going to
replace suffix.  Rather than being a
string like that we're going to have the
uniqueString() function.
If I hover over that function
you'll see that it takes at least one
argument.  All of the functions are very
useful in that you can hover over the
top of them
and it will just give a description as
to what it needs and what it's going to
do. So with uniqueString() we're going to
provide it with something to make it
vaguely unique. Now for us we just want
to make sure that we have a storage
account within this specific resource
group and so on that basis what we're
going to do is going to use the
rewsourceGroup) function. Now resourceGroup() is a
function that returns an object which has a
number of sub-properties: ID, location, name
and properties,  Wwe just need to use the
ID, so take ID and tap that in as well,
and now we have a function which is
going to seed the uniqueString with
resource group ID.
That'll give us a 13 character code.
I'm going to prefix that with
our storage account prefix and then
lowercase everything.  That's all in
place.   If I remove the spaces we don't
need just to shorten the argument a
little bit then that will tidy that up.
This is more complex than any other
expression that you're likely to put in,
using this many functions, unless you're doing
some really complicated stuff based on
conditionals later on but it's good
practice just so you can see how things
are nested and how you can pull those in
quickly. The other thing I'm going to add
in is a default for our storage crowd
prefix.  I'm going to put "richeneystg"
as my default value.
The other thing I'm going to put in
is I'm going to put in a maxLength as
well. This will take a integer value.
Because we know the uniqueString() is
going to return 13 characters, and the
maximum length for storage account name is 24
then really the max length I want my
users to be able to put in, if they
override this default, is 11 so that'll
make sure we never exceed that 24
characters.  OK, so we're done. As you can
see the last thing to do is that
storageAccount is never used. We're using
parameters rather than the variables so
we need to create that. If I just type
in variables there and for our display
name there.
We should no longer have any issues with
this workspace.  So I'll save that file and
that's ready to submit.