I've opened up the portal and
navigated into the lab1 resource group.
As you can see we've got our
storage account.
Click on deployments in the blade
on the left hand side to show the
deployment jobs and you'll see job1
has been listed there. Click on
job1 then it will open up and you can
see the overview listing the
various resources it's deployed.
Just the simple storage account for us.
You can look at what that template
looked like at that submission point in
time. If you are structured in your
naming conventions for your
deployment jobs then you can always go
back and see what's that looked like.
It automatically creates a parameters
file at the same time,
and it's got some example CLI and
PowerShell scripts you can use to call
the templates as well as some .NET and
Ruby SDK information. We can see we have
no inputs, plus we have no outputs. We'll
have some of those when we go through
things later on but that's essentially
the information you get when you are
looking via the portal.
If you're using either the
PowerShell AzureRM cmdlets or you're
using the CLI 2.0 az commands you can
get to that same information
programmatically.