Here's our template and parameter
file as exported straight from the
portal. As you can see it's been
automatically and programmatically generated,
which is great and useful, but it does
have some weird things in this
particular one. It's very common once
you've exported a template to start
customizing it to make it your own.
One of the things I see here is if I
look at my parameter file there are nine
parameters in here, most of which I don't
think need to be specified. I want to
hard-code my SKU to be a free F1 type
Web App. When it comes to the resource
group then I'm going to have my plan and
my web app in the same resource group.
I shouldn't be specifying things like
location and subscription ID, so a lot of
these things aren't relevant. Also if I
look at the template itself then again I
should be able reduce down those. There're
no variables specified at the moment.
We've also got some errors coming through for
the API version and the website version
as well. I'm going to tidy some of
these things up. First thing I'm going to
do is I'm going to move up the schema
and the content version, up to the top of
the file. It really doesn't matter to be
honest, but it's where I'm used to seeing
them, so I'm going to put those back at
the top of the file and just make sure
it's syntactically good before we start.
Now if we go to the https://aka.ms/armref
area again and we have a look
at web apps
then we'll see the API version
for that is now up to 2016-08-01.
In doing that change
we've got rid of that error.
I'm going to start removing some things which
are silly so things like using a
parameter for location. I am very happy
to ensure that these resources go into the
same location as the resource group.
There are other times when you might
want to specify things differently.
The resourceGroup().location function
is a very standard thing to put
into there and I'm going to do exactly
the same for the other one.
And for the tier and
for the name
then again we want to
go for a SKU code of F1 and a SKU of
Free.
I'm going to hard-code this so rather
than putting in a parameter, I'm just
going to set value to "Free" and likewise for the
name of SKU code, I'm going to go with "F1".
So that makes that part slightly simpler.
One of the other things you'll notice if
you have a look at the template
reference is there's absolutely no
reference at all to hostingEnvironment
so we can safely get rid of that as well.
Likewise for the workerSizeId.
Currently that is set at zero.
We can do the same with this and
again hardcode it to zero.
I've dropped out a few of the
variables just to clear those up
because you can see they're no longer
being used and we can take that set out
and remove them.  Shrunk it down quite
a lot already. Now serverFarmResourceGroup
is being used by this very
bizarre-looking tag. This is
essentially creating a tag called hidden-
related and is concatenating a number of
literal strings and parameters.
If you've gone through
the theory section you know that it's
just a standard resource ID, so why
it's not using resourceId() to generate that,
I don't know.  Essentially we're
going to get rid of that whole tag.
We have just got the standard
dependency at that point so should see
now that the serverFarmResourceGroup
isn't really doing much for us.
So serverFarmId again
we've got this concat here for that too,
we're going to change that
into a more standard function which is
resourceId() but let's do that using a
variable. Add in our variable
section and then we can have serverFarmId
- or as I'm going to put it in, webAppPlanId
- and we're going to have that
based on resourceId(). This is a
function you'll be using quite a lot.
It's good for generating the resource IDs.
It doesn't need to have that
existing resource to be able to generate it,
it's essentially generating a string value
If you hover over it you can
see it takes four arguments but you only usually
need two.  You need to name the resourceType and
the name of the resource we're going to
be generating or linking to. If you don't
specify the subscriptionID or the
resourceGroup name then it's just going
to assume that it's the subscriptionId for
the resource group you're
submitting into, likewise the
resource group name, if you've not
specified that either. It does give you
the flexibility to generate resource IDs
for resources sitting in other resource
groups or in other subscriptions.
We're just going to create
one using the hostingPlanName.
Taking 'Microsoft.Web/serverfarms', so
that'll be our first string literal and
then the second we're going to be
putting in is going to be the resource
name itself. This will be a variable
which doesn't yet exist, which I'm going
to be calling webAppPlan.
We'll start creating some additional variables
just to make life a little bit simpler.
One of those is going to be our webAppPlan,
so our webAppPlan is going to
be a concat of our
parameters('webAppName')
and then I'm going to suffix onto
that with '-plan' so then we only
specify the
webapp name and it
is automatically going to generate
that for us.
This will become webAppName up here instead.
We're not going to have
hostingPlanName or hostingEnvironment
or serverFarmResourceGroup
or subscriptionId so I'm
going to take all those out and that will
enable us to highlight where they're
not being used properly so the name for
our web app should now be webAppName.
Name is a terrible parameter to
use if you are submitting using AzureRM
cmdlets. One of the things
PowerShell does is it automatically
generates new switches based on your
parameters, so if you have one called
webAppName then it's going to create
-webAppName then you specify the
argument for that to be the name that
you want. If you have one called name
it's going to error because that
conflicts with -name which has already
been used for the name for the
deployment job. Why it's generating
the template with a "name" parameter is a good question.
I'm going to put webAppName in at that point.
This serverFarmId, we no longer need it
in that format, so I'm going to get rid of
that. We should just be able to
specify our new variable which is
webAppPlanId. Close that off.
The hostingEnvironment as we saw earlier
was blank so we don't need to specify
anything for that.
So hostingEnvironment here is a blank
value so I'm just going to take that
back to being an empty string again.
I don't believe that's being used for
anything anyway. (Only used for Isolated ASEs.)
Save that. We're dependent on
parameters('hostingPlanName') which is
now instead a variable,
and the variable is webAppPlan.
Finish off the concat. So that's sorted out
that resource. Again for the hostingPlanName,
this is now our variables('webAppPlan').
Again we can use the multiple
select for this. If I want to
get that whole thing removed then I can
do CTRL+F2, delete that and then we put
in variables and then select 'webAppPlan'
and then that's gone in instead.
We've got our webAppPlan which is
being a bit more hard-coded into what
size it's going to be but the location
is now based off the resource group and
then we have our web app itself which is
dependent on that web app plan
implicitly.  We've also got
an explicit dependency at this
level - this could be using that same
web app plan ID that - let's be consistent
do just that  - rather than just the name.
Just put that resourceId in there.
That's a much tidier shorter
template.
Save that. First check
we've got no issues. There we've got one.
There, where I have not closed off the
second brace. So that's then gone.
Save that. If I look at the parameters file
then we've got a whole host of parameters
in here which we're no longer using, so we
can get shot of all of those.
This one is now changed in terms of the
"name", of course. This is now our
"webAppName" so that should be consistent
with what's being expected by the
template itself, so that's declared that it
needs a webAppName.
Better if I could spell my own name...
And that's what it's going
to create.  so now I've got a template
and parameter file we can use.