We're now going to create a template
by exporting something out of the Azure
portal. This is a very common thing to do
if you're dealing with new resources,
and they show up in the portal
and you then want to be able to do
those programmatically.
We're going to do that by clicking on
create resource and we're going to do a
Web App here and so I select the Web App
and then once the details come up then
we will start going through. We're not
going to click on this blue Create
button, we're going to look at the
automation options down here. Let's just
put these details in. I'm going to put
a name for my web apps, "richeneyarm".
I'm also going to put it into a
new resource group called lab2.
I'm going to choose my App Service Plan,
I want to put this on the Free tier,
and hard-code this to that Free tier.
I'm going to create new and then
within that I can specify the location
which I'm going to put into West Europe.
Service plan I'll name "richeneyarm-plan".
We're going to change the tier.
There's the new dialog box for this.
We're going to change that
to dev / test and then choose
the free tier and apply OK.
We're now on the Free tier with the F1 size.
Click OK that should then take that
through.
Rather than click Create,
go into automation options.
This automatically generates JSON files
for both the parameter file and
template file which gives us a useful
starting point for taking these and then
customizing. That's what we want to do so
if I click into the area for the main
pane and do CTRL-A and CTRL-C to copy
the contents of that, I can then click
back over to our Visual Studio Code area.
Then if I create a new file,
called "lab2/azuredeploy.json",
then I can paste the contents into
there.  And save the file.
Create a new file
that is called
azuredeploy.parameters.json.
And then when we go back we can select
parameters file, take the contents of that
and paste that in, and that gives us the
two files ready for us to start
customizing.