Before we move on with lab 2, just
want to go through API versions very
quickly. If I navigate using the
JSON outline tool down to our resources
and our storage account,
then what you see at the top of the
file is very standard.  We have the
type which is our resource
provider / resource type.  We then have
the name for the resource, the API
version, and then the location.
This could be in any order you want.
Location is commonly set to the same
location as the resource group itself so
again West Europe for the resource group.
The API version as you can see here is the
15th June 2015 so this is not a
particularly new one. As new features get
added into the various Azure services
then if they require additional
properties to go into the ARM JSON
standard for that resource type then the schema
gets updated for that resource.
I'm going to take a copy of the resource type.
"Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts"
Go to a browser and go to
https://aka.ms/armref.
That'll take us through to the ARM
reference area.  It's very structured
in the way it is organized.  You can
navigate through just browsing on the
left hand side into the various
providers and then into the resource
types and sub resources whin those.
Or you can append to the URL at
the top here and put in the provider
type and that'll take you straight
through to the reference page.
You get a full resource
template description.
It shows you the API version.
This is February 2018 and it has some
information for the properties
within it and some of the
sub objects that form the fuller
definition so if you want to have a look
at v2 storage accounts or anything to do with
encryption then you'll see the
additional detail within there.