Here's our VM template. This is the
one which is making use of the Key Vault
secret for the admin password,
sending that through as a securestring.
By default, at the bottom of
this template we have two outputs.
One for the hostname and one for the ssh
command. There are times when you
want to output additional information,
and this is how I go about doing it.
I make use of the reference() function.
You can see it being called
with the standard outputs I have
here. This is the way you'd normally see
it. You just pass in a resourceId. You
can see there's a vmId variable. If I move
up to there for a second that is just a
standard resourceId passing in the
'Microsoft.Compute/virtualmachines'
resource type and then the name
of the resource itself using
parameters('vmName'). There is another
way of calling reference and
that is by passing in the optional
second and third values to the function
call. The second one is the apiVersion
and the third one is 'full'.
That takes the JSON output it gives
you and pulls it up a level, giving
you some additional information around
the deployment type and other
information for that resource.
You'll see that the standard information
we have is actually the
properties value within 'full'.
Feel free to play with
using the 'full' argument
yourself. We are going to
take a look at the standard output.
Let me just rework my screen and bring
up the terminal. If I do
'az group deployment list' and have a look at
the app3 resourceGroup.
I'll do that as table output.
That should show that we have got one
deployment job, fairly recently run, and
it's called azuredeploy. I didn't
specify a name, it's just
the basename for the template.
If I run 'az group deployment show' and
again '--resourceGroup lab3', the name of
the deployment job, '--name azuredeploy' and
then we're going to do the output.
Normally I use output in jsonc (coloured
JSON), but I'll do this in standard uncoloured
JSON because we're going to copy this
and use it in a tool so we can drill
down into it more easily. I'm going
to do a standard JMESPATH query. Have a
look at https://aka.ms/citadel/guides if
you want to see some more information
about how to do these. Query on
properties.outputs. Within that
we're then going to drill into the
"standard" output we just created
and see the value of that. If that runs
successfully then this is what we'll see.
There's quite a lot of
information coming out for the virtual
machine resourceID. Now I'm just going to
take that information and copy it out,
and go to the browser.  Now this is
https://jqplay.org.  If you've seen
the guides, you'll have noticed me talking
about jq as a command.  And jqplay is one
way you can find out how to query some
JSON output and formulate one of those
jq command lines. It's also useful for
getting the dot notation we can then use
within templates. If I paste in our
JSON, into the area on the left hand
side, with jq, "." outputs everything on the
right hand side. We can then start
drilling into it.  If I wanted to put
in the diagnosticsProfile
then you can see that auto
filters it down.
It is filtered down to that section of
that JSON.  Instead we wanted to
get into
the storage profile. So let's
change that to .storageProfile
so you've got storage
profile and then that should
automatically start drilling into that and
then if we typed ".osDisk" again it will
filter it down further another level
down and it's the ID within the
managedDisk section. So, add on
".managedDisk.id" and that should then
give us the actual ID for the OS disk.
If you're using jq command you would
normally do the raw output
and that will strip off the
speech marks.  Like using
"--output tsv", i.e. tab separated values.
When you're using that. So that is the
pathing convention we're going to use.
I'll get rid of
the 'full'. Instead of
outputting "standard", outputs "osDiskId".
That would now
be a string rather than an object.
As well as pulling out the the reference
for the variable ID we're now going to
paste the .storageProfile.osDisk.managedDisk.id
and that should
pull out that particular ID and outputs it.
Save that and run it.