Let's test this conditional template
by submitting it twice. Once
creating a virtual machine which has a
public IP,  and once again where we do not
specify the dnsLabelPrefix so that it
shouldn't create the pip, and will define
the NIC differently as a result. You'll
notice that in the output section I have
removed all of the properties within
that object. That's because we have the
public IP address as one of those
outputs so just to make life simple I've
removed that for the moment.
Let's open up the integrated terminal.
I'm going to go into the lab4 folder
where our files are sitting and I'm going to
create a lab4 resource group and
put into West Europe as per normal.
As I'm deploying a couple I'm going to
create myself an alias. This is one thing
you can do in Bash. So I'm going to do an
alias and I'm going to call my alias
'deploy' and that is going to be set to
'az group deployments create'. I'm not
going to specify name or parameters as I want to
be able to control those but in terms of
the resource group I'm going to default
that to be whatever folder I'm in at the
moment so I'll make that the basename
of whatever we print for the working
directory where we are the moment. That
should return lab4. Then I'm going
to specify my template file as
azuredeploy.json.
That will save me a little bit typing in a second.
If I do "alias deploy",
you can see that's been set
successfully.  So let's then then deploy
using that command. Imagine
that's been replaced by that whole
command, and then I'm going to set the
name for first deployment job as public
and for that we're going to specify our
parameters file so that will be
"@azuredeploy.parameters.json"
and I'm also going to have a couple
of inline overrides specifying
vmName=public and
dnsLabelPrefix=richeneypublicvm.
So let's submit that. I'm also going
to put in a --no-wait so I'm just going to
have that deploying in the background. That
should submit the job with those two
within it. I'm then going to do exactly
the same again, but I'm going to change
some of these. I will get rid of
the dnsLabelPrefix, I'm going to change
that to private and I'll change that one
to private. Not a great naming convention
for you virtual machines but it should
show what we've got. And if we do a
deployment list for our resource group
lab4 then you should see the two
jobs are sitting within there. I'll do
that as a table so it's a bit more
readable and there's our two running
jobs. So I'll have a look at those in a minute
once it's created but in the meantime we
should be able to have a look at the
resources and list those out for our
resource group. By the way you can see
I'm using the --resource-groups switch a lot
of times. I probably want to use
"as configure --defaults" if
you're doing a lot of commands in a
resource group and specify "group=lab4".
Hopefully it has
started creating some of the resources.
If you remember the public IP addresses
are not contingent on anything else,
they've got no dependency so they should
be created straight away so you can see
the public NIC and the public PIP is
being created but we only have a private
NIC so that's already looking quite
good. I'll pipe those to sort so they're in a
slightly better order. OK, so there you
can see that for the private one we've
got just a NIC,
for the public one we've got both
a NIC and a PIP.
That's coming through quite neatly. Good.