The work we're going to do during lab 4 is
a continuation of what we started in lab
3 so I'll be copying forward that
directory in a minute.
That'll be the same at the end of this
lab as well, as we move into the Copies
in lab 5 that'll be an extension of the
work we've done in this one, so you'll do the
same again at the end of this lab.
Let's show you how that's done.  If I
highlight lab 3 and then do CTRL+C,
CTRL+V to copy and paste it then you
can see it's pasted it in as lab 4.
It increments the number for us.
Right, let's look at the azuredeploy.json.
Now what we're going to do within this is
we're going to make the public IP
address creation - so you can see that's
one of the resources we have within this -
we're going to make that conditional on
whether or not the DNS label prefix has
been set.  First thing we're going to do
is put in an empty string for that as
the default value.
That means that if it's not
being specified by the user,
it's going to use an empty string
as the default value and then we can use
that to control whether or not it gets
created. The other change we want to do
within this parameters declaration area
is remove the default value for the
virtual machine.
Save those changes. So that now
means that we're using the parameters
file for all of the customer specific
user information around the admin
credentials so they have username and
the password secretname we're pulling
from the Key Vault, and likewise for the
virtual network naming conventions as
well. For the submission specific
parameters we're going to do those as
inline parameters.  Virtual machine name we're
always going to specify that as it's now
required at submission time and we can
optionally use the dnsLabelPrefix to
control whether or not we're going to
have a public IP address and FQDN created.
I'll close down the parameters file.
If I close down the parameters section
You can use CTRL-SHIFT
and use the square brackets "[]".
I'm going to do the
same for storage accounts because
there's no changes to be done there. Let's
have a look at the public IP address.
I want this whole resource to be
conditionally created dependent on
whether or not we have anything
specified within dnsLabelPrefix.
Condition is one of the
remaining top-level
control words we can use.
The condition is going to
want an expression after that which
evaluates to either boolean true or
false. If you have a look at the
https://aka.ms/armfunc area or the function
documentation for ARM templates you'll
see there's a number of different
functions which return boolean
true or false.
Including the bool() function itself.
We have function like empty(), we
have greater(), less(), equals(), so
there's a whole host of different
functions you can use which return
boolean true or false. We're going to be
using empty().
The empty() function basically looks at either
a string or an array or an object, and returns
true or false dependent on whether it is
populated.  We're going to feed that
with parameters() and select the
dnsLabelPrefix and close that off so now
that's going to return true if dnsLabelPrefix
is empty, and false if it isn't.
That's actually the reverse of what
we want to see so we're going to invert
that result by surrounding the expression with the
not() function instead.  As it says, not()
will take whatever boolean value
has been passed into it and give its
opposite value instead.  Now if our
dnsLabelPrefix is not empty then we're going to
create the public IP address. If it is
empty then i'm going to skip this whole
resource and not creat it.  That's how you
use conditions against full resources.
OK, I'm going to close down virtual
networks because there has nothing
within it which is public IP specific so
let's shrink that down and let's have a
look at the network interfaces instead.
There are two sections within this
which we're going to concentrate on.
One is the explicit dependencies and as you
can see here we have explicit
dependencies for both the public IP
address resource and also for the
virtual network resource. The other
section we're going to look at is this
public IP address section down here.
Now this, as a property within the
ipConfigurations properties area,
is optional in itself.  We have it
included because we're using a public IP
address, but if we were doing an internal
NIC then this section will probably look
like that instead. So it wouldn't even
include that but one of the things you
can do within JSON within the ARM
templates is at runtime it will quite
happily take that null value.
As it has got a null value for that
name value pair it's just going to
ignore publicIpAddress and won't
include that.
Pet's just put that back for a second.  I'm
going to take a copy of that block there.
We're going to put an if() statement in
there instead, saying that if our
dnsLabelPrefix is populated we're
going to put in that object and if it isn't
we're going to put in null. You want to
create an object for that in the
variables section. I'm not talking about
the ID to resourceIs() (name:value) pair that
we've got there, I'm talking about the whole
object. We need to include the braces
for that so I'm going to copy that
whole section there and then we'll go
back up to the variables and add in a
new pipObject and set the value
of that to be the whole of that object
so including the curly braces. We're
not using that yet which is why it's got
a yellow underline warning.
Because we're now going to
repeat this test here, we might as
well make that into a variable as well.
Again I'm going to take that whole
expression and then we'll create a new
boolean variable. Now for boolean
variables I quite often use the question
mark just to denote that it is a boolean.
Question mark, despite being a special
character normally, is permitted within
the naming convention so I'm going to
leverage that there and then I'll put
that expression, followed by a comma.
Now our "pip?" boolean is going to
be set based on that expression which
means that we can now change our
condition at the top of the public IP
address resource.  Rather than having the
whole expression we can now use our
variable.  That'll get
evaluated into either the
boolean true or false value and create
that public IP resource depending
on that expression evaluation.
Now we need to work on this section
here.  We need to replace this whole
section so again I'm going to take the
whole of the object, including the
curly braces, and delete that.n
we'll start putting in a new expression
here.  The function we're going to use
is if(), and as it says there
if(condition, true, false). It's got three
elements to it so I'm going to put those
in just as placeholders so condition,
true, false, just so you can see how this
gets constructed and then I'll close
that off.  Now the condition we're going
to use is the same as we used at the top
of the PIP resource, so if our "pip?"
boolean is true or false and find out
whether or not we create it.  If it
returns true then we want to put in that
pipObject.   Use CTRL+SPACE
to pull up the list and put in
variables, and add in the
object. If it's false we want to put
in null.  We want to put in the null
JSON object.  You can't just type in
null at this point because that will not
be accepted.
And you can't put null in single quotes
because that will be a literal string.
The way that you put in null so it gets
accepted properly is by using the json()
function.  So json() as a function
takes one argument, and
you can feed it JSON as string -
you have to escape speech marks and
things like that  - and it will then
convert that into a JSON object.
We can add in single quotes surrounding
null and that'll be accepted. I'll just
close with a bracket so it matches up.  That
is a valid if() statement against that
public IP address. A couple of things
to bear in mind. We need the pip object
we'll need the pip boolean and then we
can use it within that section. That
is the easiest way to control how you
construct different sections of your
properties within a resource. Save the
file and let's try some submitting it.