Let's add the snippets into
Visual Studio Code. If you open up this
snippets file -  so this is provided by Sam
Cogan -  and do CTRL-A and CTR-C to
copy the contents from that file and then go
to vscode.  You can go through the file menu
to get to the User Snippet if you want.
File -> Preferences -> User Snippets.
The quickest way is to use the Settings cog
and then choose User Snippets from there
and if you search for json.json in
the list to open.
This is the default file.
You can see this one is empty, it's just
got the opening and closing brace, top and
bottom, and then some comments which are
slightly outside of the JSON standard.
If I hit enter where the cursor is now
I'll take it down within that section
and then we can paste the contents of
the snippets into there. Now I'm just
going to do CTRL+SHIFT+M to show any
errors and there's a pull request
against these at the moment because
there's a missing comma in the file.
You can see that if I put one here
I'll get rid of that red line against
dependsOn and then it's syntactically
good. If you've got Eric Lynd's
JSON tools you can do CTRL+ALT+M
against the whole file and that will
just slightly tidy up everything within
it. Save the file (CTRL+S).
As you can see it's got the little round
dot to show it's got unsaved changes.
Save the file and you can
close it down. Right, to test that
everything's working type CTRL+N and that will
create a new file.  We'll call it test.json.
I'm just going to put this
straight into my downloads folder and name it
test.json and by doing that it will it'll
automatically know it's a JSON file at
the bottom right here, which means it's
going to start picking up on the
snippets.  If I type "arm" at this
point then you should see this list of
snippets come up as soon as you do that.
If I pick the top one which is the
skeleton arm template, hit enter at that
point and then do CTRL+S to save those
changes.  That is our default ARM
template and our snippets are working.